Self-driven and analytical team player with 13 years of military experience. A diligent individual who thrives on problem-solving and getting the details right while delivering to time and target. Excited for opportunities to be at the forefront of advancements in IT.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### Frontend

- Proficient in HTML, CSS, SASS, PostCSS,
- Proficient in Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, Shadon
- Proficient in JavaScript, TypeScript
- Proficient in Node.js, Express.js
- Experience with React, Next.js, Angular
- Experience with Jest and Playwright

#### Backend

- Experience with Azure, Bicep and Terraform
- Experience with Redis
- Experience with Keycloak
- Experience with Python
- Experience with Linux
- Knowledge of MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

### Version control

• Proficient in Git, GitHub

### DevOps

- Experience with Docker, Podman
- Knowledge of GitHub Actions
- Knowledge of OpenShift, ArgoCD

# Security

- Experience with OWASP Zap
- Knowledge of SonarQube, Anchore

# Project Management

- Proficient in Jira, Confluence
- Experience with Agile methodologies

### **EXPERIENCE**

# FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Ministry of Defence (Contract), With You With Me | 2023 – Present

- Worked as part of an agile team to deliver web applications with a focus on current content, security and accessibility.
- Front-end development using JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Express, and Docker.
- Translated UX designs into functional code, leveraging Government and MOD Design Systems to standardise multiple websites.
- Developed a custom-themed and security-hardened Keycloak instance enabling sensitive content to be hosted.
- Set up a Redis Enterprise instance for secure session management
- Tested security using OWASP ZAP, leading to hardened code and successful penetration tests.
- Created unit tests using Jest and end-to-end tests using Playwright to ensure robust and efficient code.
- Used Microsoft Azure Communication Services to create a Python-based custom communications centre app with Interactive Voice Response that will be used internationally for potential crisis situations.
- Used Bicep and Terraform to create infrastructure as code (IaC) configurations for Azure-based apps.
- Authored comprehensive technical documentation and diagrams to detail both code and team processes.
- Employed Git and GitHub for version control, ensuring code integrity and collaboration.
- Set up automated GitHub Actions to pre-emptively identify formatting errors and security issues before deployment.
- Utilised Jira and Confluence for efficient project management.
- Liaised with senior management to plan and execute projects in an Agile manner.

### EXPERIENCE CONTINUED...

#### **TEAM LEADER**

British Army | 2010 - 2023

- Performed as part of a large multi-disciplinary team producing world-class ceremonial music for high-profile military, royal, and charity engagements globally.
- Successfully led and managed multiple teams on time-sensitive projects to achieve high standards of completion.
- Provided first-line incident response within the London Central Garrison to maintain vital security.
- Mentored, trained, and ensured welfare of new employees.

# **EDUCATION**

# **BEng (Hons) Automotive Engineering**

University of Huddersfield 2002 - 2006

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **NETWORK+**

CompTIA

Completed: March 2023

### **AZURE AZ-104**

Microsoft

In progress

### ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Army Reservist
- Mountain Bike Instructor
- Freelance musician
- Music composition and arrangement for professional musical ensembles